Guide to the Soroptimist International of Missoula-South Records 1978-1990
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Guide to the Soroptimist International of Missoula-South Records
1978-1990
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana—Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 879
Soroptimist International of Missoula-South
1.0 linear feet 2 boxes
This collection consists of records from the South Missoula chapter of Soroptimist International, an international women's service organization for business and professional women who work to improve the lives of women and girls in local communities and throughout the world. The collection contains administrative records, photographs and memorabilia from events, 1978-1990s.
Historical Note
Soroptimist (a name coined by combining the Latin words soror "sister" and optimus "best", and can be taken to mean "best for women") was founded in 1921 in Alameda County, California. Montana’s Soroptimist International of Missoula – South chapter chartered March 29, 1978. This branch began a variety of community service programs including assisting with the local battered woman’s shelter, scholarship pageants, and youth seminars. By 2005 the organization was no longer active.
This collection includes many photos, dating between 1978 and 1990, showing various members and member functions; newsletters written and sent out by the chapter president; correspondence between members; and files relating to a variety of community outreach programs, including a Regional Youth Seminar.
This collection has been divided into three series:
Series I: Administrative Files, 0.3 linear feet, 1978-1990
Series II: Photographs, 0.2 linear feet, circa 1980s
Series III: Scrapbook, 0.5 linear feet, 1978
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana-Missoula.
This collection was given to the Historical Museum at Ft. Missoula on March 15, 2005 by an anonymous donor. The collection was transferred by the Museum to the Archives at UM in June 2005.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Soroptimist International of Missoula--Archives
Missoula (Mont.)--Social conditions--20th century
Women--Services for--Montana--Missoula; Women--Montana--Missoula--Societies and clubs; Women's shelters--Montana--Missoula
Women; Montana
- Administrative Files, 1978-1990; Series I; 0.3 linear feet
  This series contains information on bylaws, orgainzational procedures, newsletters and seminars
  - Bylaws of Soroptimist of Missoula-South Operating Files, 1979 and undated (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Community Service, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1986 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Memorabilia and conference material, circa 1982 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - News Clippings, 1978-1990 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Newsletters, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Northwestern Regional Youth Seminar, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Soroptimist International Guides and Procedures, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 1/8)
- Photographs, 1980s; Series II; 0.2 linear feet
  The photographs are of events, parties, officer installations and Soroptimist fundraisers.
  - Photographs, circa 1980s (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Photograph album pages, 1980s (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Slides and negatives, undated (Box-folder 1/11)
- Scrapbook, 1978; Series III; 0.5 linear feet
  The scrapbook contains photographs, invitations, letters and assorted memorabila.
  - Scrapbook, 1978 (Box OS 2)